[
	{
		"question": "Where was the first Communist Party of India formed?",
		"options": ["Meerut","Tashkent","Moscow","Kanpur"],
		"answer": "b",
		"category": "CPI History"
	},
	{
		"question": "*this* conspiracy case gave boost to communist movement in India?",
		"options": ["Bombay","Nagpur","Meerut","Kanpur"],
		"answer": "c",
		"category": "CPI History"
	},
	{
		"question": "When did the first workers' international take place?",
		"options": ["28 Sept 1864","25 Mar 1866","24 Apr 1885","22 Feb 1883"],
		"answer": "a",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},
{
		"question": "In which worker's international did the split between anarchists and Marxists happen?",
		"options": ["Pragur conference","Hague Conference","Yalta Conference","Berlin Conference"],
		"answer": "b",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},
	{
		"question": "What was the name of the first book Engels wrote?",
		"options": ["Anti Duhring","The origin of family, private property and the state","Dialectics of nature","The condition of the working class in England"],
		"answer": "d",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},
{
		"question": "On which date was the Paris commune established?",
		"options": ["18 Mar 1871","17 Oct 1873","15 Nov 1871","19 Aug 1875"],
		"answer": "a",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},
{
		"question": "When did the Paris commune end?",
		"options": ["15 Dec 1875","7 May 1871","12 Jan 1872","11 Jun 1873"],
		"answer": "b",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},

{
		"question": "For which newspaper did Marx write?",
		"options": ["Rheinische Zeitung","Allegemeine Zeitung","Die Germantauner Zeitung","Die Philadelphische Zeitung"],
		"answer": "a",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},
{
		"question": "Where was the Communist Manifesto first published?",
		"options": ["Berlin","London","Moscow","Brussels"],
		"answer": "b",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},
{
		"question": "Where is Karl Marx's grave situated?",
		"options": ["Highgate cemetery","Brompton cemetery","Nunhead cemetery","Barnes cemetery"],
		"answer": "a",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	},	
{
		"question": "What did Marx study in college?",
		"options": ["Medicine and philosophy","Philosophy and theology","Sociology and theology","Law and philosophy"],
		"answer": "d",
		"category": "Marx and Engels"
	}
]
